Introduction of objects of interest,
starting outside sampled region.
Connected arteries (red) and veins (blue) with capillaries up to a proximity of about 30 µm together with adjacent terminal bronchioles (Bt, grey) and beginning of its acinus.
Largest part of an acinus (Acn, light grey) contained within sampled region.
Capillary network (ACN-Acn magenta) in proximity of Acn up to about 10 µm.
View along an alveolar duct that extends beyond the z-depth of the sampled region.
Note: no tissue is rendered. This leads to the gaps between e.g. Bt and Acn.
Beginning to follow a possible path of an O2 molecule.
Camera now enters sampled region.
Right side of Bt is just about contained in the sampled region.
Multiple airway bifurcations appear nearly at the same position.
Bumps in the surface of Bt are no artefacts,
but apparent terraces are.
About to enter a connected acinus (not Acn),
which mostly lies outside the sampled region.
# Reaching the bronchoalveolar duct junction (BADJ), where a minimal constriction of the airway exists.
# or the surface covering the rim of the tubular ending of non-parenchymal tissue about x µm further on.
Artefacts originating from fragmented tissue are present in this region of the dataset.
The first alveoli are about reached. These are significantly smaller than the average.
Camera now exits sampled region.
Start of the transition from Bt to Acn, used to outline further details from an over view.
An unobscured view of the ACN contained within the septa is given at the opened surfaces at the borders of the dataset.
As the vessel system is incomplete, the ACN is coloured magenta except in the proximity of the arteries and veins.
There a distance gradient is coloured from red to blue.
Vessel connection outside the dataset can lead to false colouring at the borders of the dataset.
Visible alveoli now have their standard size.
The increased transparency of Bt reveals the underlying capillaries.
The vessel segments are smoothed less in order to preserve their finer details in comparison to the air segment.
Parts of Acn (light grey) are now in view.
As the ACN is only rendered in near proximity, visual distinction between inner and outer side of Acn, Bt is easy.
Some regions of the ACN do not suffer from missing connections, see marks.
Most missing connection in the ACN originate from remaining erythrocytes and not from reconstruction artefacts.
Beginning to close up on the largest duct entry of Acn.
Many ducts branching off can be observed, a particular ordering is not obvious.
Small, outward bumps on the alveolar surface likely originate from macrophages.
Camera now enters sampled region again.
An arteriole (red) embedded in septa comes into view.
Further inside the dataset, the ACN is more complete.
Removing transparency to allow focusing on the arrangement of alveoli.
A particular ordering is not obvious.
Viewing along the open duct towards the camera position when it was first pointed out.
Closing up on an alveolar cluster referred to as A45.
The ACN surrounding A45 (ACN-A45) was manually refined to also include erythrocytes (red segments).
The white line within the ACN indicates the path we are going to follow.
Transitioning from the air lumen through the gas diffusion area into the blood lumen.
A cylinder with a length of 5 µm to indicate the scale.
About to pass through the tightest constriction (about 1 to 2 µm) along the whole path taken.